恶魔城
第四季 第５集
白天出发肯定会更安全
Surely it would have been safer to do this during daylight.
‎我们本来就应该在白天转移
We would have been expected to do this during daylight.
‎虽然我们称他们为"黑暗生物"
We may call them night creatures,
‎但他们在阳光下行动自如
but they operate perfectly when in sunshine.
‎但可以肯定 ‎指挥他们的吸血鬼受不了白天
But surely the vampires who command them are disadvantaged by daylight.
‎他们的黑暗生物显然听从命令
Their night creatures are clearly being instructed.
‎这些攻击目标很明确
The attacks are too targeted.
‎所以我们要在他们接到新命令前转移
So we're moving before they can be given fresh orders.
是的 希望这样能活下来
We live in hope, yes.
‎我们有机会赶在被他们发现
And our chances of making it to your castle
‎下达新命令之前到达你的城堡吗
before we're spotted and those fresh orders are given?
‎我想 几乎没什么机会
Oh, somewhere between slim and none, I would imagine.
‎要是我想听你说话 ‎我会往你的乞讨碗里扔钱的
When I want to hear from you, I'll throw a coin in your begging bowl.
‎所有这一切 还有魔法流浪汉
All this and a magical tramp.
‎"魔法"
"Magical"?
‎我一辈子都住在这里
I've lived out here my whole life.
‎我们住在森林和溪流的精灵旁边
We live next to the spirits of wood and stream,
它们伴随着暴风雨和魔法的气息而来
the things that come with the storm and the smell of magic.
‎你能闻出来 ‎他散发着这种气息
You smell of it. He reeks of it.
‎你觉得闻起来是什么气息
What does it smell like to you?
‎你的气息像香料一样甜
On you, it's sweet like spices.
‎他身上是腐烂的味道
On him, it's rotten.
‎是啊 我的耳朵都快腐烂聋了
Yes, it's... it's rendered me quite deaf.
‎我只是个学者 夫人
I am but a scholar, madam.
‎你闻到的气息要归功于‎阿鲁卡多最近用的香皂
The scents you detect are entirely down to Alucard having recently used soap
‎而我要和你的鸡争着用池塘里的水
and my having to fight your chickens for access to pond water.
‎还争输了
And losing.
‎确实输了 我是个学者
And indeed losing. I am a man of books.
‎我很不喜欢你那土里土气的农民做派
Your earthy peasant ways are quite beyond me.
‎我有其他方面的专长
My skills lie in other directions.
‎真遗憾 ‎我希望你擅长用刀
Pity. I was hoping you were good with a knife.
‎我要巡视一圈 确保没有人掉队
I'm going to circle around and make sure I don't have stragglers.
‎只是个学者吗
Just a scholar, then?
‎还很擅长发明饮料
Well, and very good at inventing drinks.
‎我以前认识的一个人会喜欢你这一点
I used to know someone who would have liked that about you.
‎我以前认识的一个人喜欢我这一点
I used to know someone who liked that about me.
‎我希望很快能再见到她
I hope to see her again soon.
‎我希望你如愿 ‎你的话听起来令人欣慰
I hope you do. That sounds comforting.
噢 是的 ‎谢谢
Oh, yes. Thank you.
‎继续走
Keep walking.
‎没错
That's right.
‎不准你们求救
No calls for help from you.
‎这看起来是不是太辛苦了
Doesn't it look absolutely bloody exhausting?
‎快走 老兄
Move, man!
‎你没想过把箭从他脑袋里取出来吗
Could you seriously not have considered taking the arrow out of his brain?
‎拔出来就行了
Just pull the thing out.
‎不能直接拔箭
You can't just pull arrows out.
‎如果把箭拽出来 ‎箭头后面的倒钩
The barbs on the back of the arrowhead tear the flesh open
会把肉撕裂
if you yank the thing free.
‎你知道他已经死了吗
You do know he's already dead?
‎你想醒来时眼窝里插着箭吗
Would you want to wake up with an arrowhead filling your eye socket?
‎好了 现在...
There.  Now...
‎带下一个过来前 ‎试着先动动脑子 好吗
let's try thinking for a moment before bringing the next one in, shall we?
‎你重返人间了 喘口气
You're back in the world. Take a breath.
‎这里现在是你的家
This is your place now.
‎这两个人会给你做标记 ‎把你送到你要去的地方
These two will mark you out and take you where you need to be.
‎下一个
Next.
‎我能不能说...
Can I just say...
‎我觉得这个渎神的过程令人恶心
that I find this whole blasphemous process disgusting?
‎那你为什么还坐在那里看
Then why are you sitting there watching it?
‎因为我想好好表达厌恶
Because I want to hate it properly.
‎你没有别的事要做吗
Don't you have anything better to do?
‎不 在外面等我叫你们
No. Wait outside until I call you.
‎有什么事 丽诺尔
What's wrong, Lenore?
‎没什么 你觉得能有什么事
Nothing's wrong. What makes you say something's wrong?
‎我有眼睛和耳朵 ‎我知道有些事不对劲
I've got eyes and ears. I know when something's wrong.
‎好吧
All right.
‎如果卡米拉独自离开太久
When Carmilla's left on her own for too long,
‎她就开始谋划
she starts to scheme,
‎这对我们来说真的很好
and that works out really well for us.
施第里尔可能是世界上最古老的吸血鬼的稳定领地
Styria might be the oldest stable vampire community in the world,
‎当然也是女性执掌的唯一领地
certainly the only one run by women.
‎我太高兴了
I'm overjoyed.
‎闭嘴
Shush.
‎莫拉娜和斯崔格走了
Morana and Striga are away.
‎我忙着接手莫拉娜的部分工作
I've been busy taking care of some of Morana's work
‎花时间和你待在一起
and spending time with you,
‎卡米拉总是独自行事
and Carmilla's been on her own a lot.
‎现在 你知道施第里尔是怎么维持这么长时间的吗
Now, do you know how Styria has lasted so long?
‎因为你们是聪明伶俐的吸血鬼姐妹吗
Because you're all very clever vampire sisters?
‎你还真是观察入微
You've been paying attention.
‎是的 但也是因为我们没有过度扩张
Yes, but also because we didn't overreach.
‎吸血鬼天性饥渴 丽诺尔
Vampires are thirsty, Lenore.
‎这是你们的本性
It's what defines you.
‎在附近的田野里总是有地方可以吸血
There's always more blood to be drunk somewhere across the next field.
‎但我们没有那样做 真的
But we didn't do that, not really.
‎但现在我…
But now I'm...
‎我不知道...
I don't know, and it's...
这让我感到有点迷失了
It's leaving me feeling a bit lost.
‎好像我在我们体系里的地位被抹杀了
Like my place in our system has been erased.
‎我觉得你是我要解决的最后的难题
I think you were the last problem I had to solve.
‎是的 再次谢谢你
Yes. Thanks again for that.
‎闭嘴 你玩得挺开心
Oh, shush. You were having fun.
‎嗯 直接说正题吧
Well, right up until almost the end.
‎但你要说的是另一件事
But you're making another point.
‎难怪我这么喜欢你
This is why I like you.
‎你可以认真听我说
You're capable of actually listening to me.
‎也许等到我老死了 ‎你才能说完另一件事
Maybe you'll reach your other point before I die of old age.
‎我们四个人相互扶持
The four of us support each other.
‎但很快我就没事可做了
But soon I'll have nothing to do.
‎没有用处了
Nothing to offer.
‎不用外交手段 ‎也能让人类排队等着被吸血
There's no diplomacy involved in making humans stand in line to be bled.
‎所有的人类
All the humans.
‎-而且不只是在欧洲  ‎-是吗
- And not just in Europe. - Oh?
‎她给我看了她的地图
She showed me her maps.
‎我想 我惹她生气了
I made her angry, I think.
‎她给我看了世界地图
She showed me maps of the world.
‎我知道 我知道
I know, I know.
‎从这里到布勒伊拉 ‎巨大的人类畜栏 我听说了
A giant human pen from here to Braila. I've had the lectures.
‎不仅如此
Not anymore.
‎她一直在谋划
She's been scheming.
‎她给我看了世界地图 赫克托
And she showed me maps of the world, Hector.
‎世界
The world.
‎这个畜栏是为了确保我们 ‎以后几百年的生存和保障
The pen was about securing our survival and safety for centuries to come.
‎这是个疯狂的想法 ‎但我们能延续和实施这个计划
It was an insane idea, but we could stretch and make it work.
‎但现在 她看到了无处不在的弱点
But now she sees weakness everywhere.
‎我们曾经是强大而稳定的领地
And we were a strong and stable community
‎在这个世界上 ‎许多吸血鬼领袖死在布勒伊拉
in a world that lost many of its vampire leaders at Braila.
‎所以你是说 如果真是这样的情况 她会去征服世界
So what you're saying is if it's there, she's going to drink it.
‎她说她有个计划
She said she had one plan:
‎吞并从这里到海洋的土地
To annex land from here to the sea.
‎她向我保证 那是她的计划
She promised me that was her plan,
‎然后她就独自离去
and then she was left alone,
‎后来我惹她生气 她就给我看了地图
and then I made her angry and she showed me her maps.
‎我觉得她骗了你
I think she lied to me.
‎就像德古拉骗了我一样
Just the way Dracula lied to me.
‎看 他们死了
Look at them die!
‎我知道你们都又累又怕
I know you're all tired and scared,
‎但他们只是该死的畜生
but they're just bloody animals!
‎杀了那些杂种
Kill the bastards!
‎我的家人几代前来到这里
My family came here generations ago.
‎据说他们逃离了罗马人的魔爪
They escaped from the Romans, so the story goes.
‎你的家族可能起源于迦太基 ‎也许是更远的地方
You could probably trace your family back to Carthage, perhaps further.
‎我的家族就在这里
My family's here.
‎从德内什蒂建成和命名以来 ‎我们一直住在这里
We've been in Danesti since it was just a wide spot in the road.
‎人们从四面八方来到这里定居
People from all over wash up here and stay.
‎我们的起源地不是别处
We don't trace back to anywhere.
‎我们都来自这里
We're all from here.
‎起源于某个地方
That must be nice,
‎一定很不错
to be from somewhere.
‎好吧...
Well...
‎我们已经不在那里了
we're not there anymore.
‎说来惭愧
And then, I'm ashamed to say,
‎我像父亲一样 ‎把他们挂在城堡外的木桩上
I put them on stakes outside the castle like I was my father.
‎好吧
Okay.
‎我只想说
I'm just saying,
‎我的状态不太好
I am not at my best.
‎确实很…
It has been...
‎艰难
difficult.
‎我看得出来
I can see that.
‎我曾经同时有男朋友和女朋友
I mean, I had a boyfriend and a girlfriend at the same time once,
‎但他们没打算杀我
but they never tried to kill me.
‎其实 不是这样的 我说谎了
Actually, no. I tell a lie.
‎他妻子拿着干草叉来打我
His wife went for me with a pitchfork.
‎我知道你很古怪
I knew you'd be strange,
‎但我没想到 ‎这种事情会让你回归生活
but I didn't think it would be something like this that brought you back to life.
‎一直有这样的事情
It's always something like this.
‎战争吗
A war?
‎总是看起来像战争
It always looks like a war.
‎但其实是拯救
But really, it's a rescue.
‎独处 然后战斗 拯救
Alone. Then the fight. The rescue.
‎然后再独处
Then alone.
‎我也许应该完全长大了 ‎现在就接受现实
I should probably grow all the way up and accept it now.
‎还有更糟的事情
There are worse things.
‎你可能屁股上插着棍子 被‎挂在别人的城堡外面
You could be outside someone else's castle with a stake up your bum.
‎他们似乎掌握诀窍了
They seem to be getting the hang of it.
‎像你说的 他们累了
As you said, they were tired.
‎这种日子过得太久了
They've been living through this too long.
‎不想被打扰是很正常的
It's only natural to want to sleep through it.
‎听起来像是你的经验
That sounded like you spoke from experience.
‎好像是很久以前的事了
It seems like a long time ago.
‎德拉甘 你这该死的笨蛋
Dragan, you bloody fool.
‎要是你演的这出好戏把我们都害死了
If this little show you're putting on gets us all killed,
‎那就白干了
this was for nothing.
‎我不会后退的
I'm not backing off.
‎给我点空间就行
Just give me some space.
‎我是来应战的
I came to do a job.
‎我请求你允许我来出手
I'm asking your permission to do it.
‎好的
All right.
‎德古拉的城堡
Dracula's castle.
‎令人惊叹
Astonishing.
‎真的很…
It's really quite...
‎难看死了
Ugly as sin.
‎不难看
It's not ugly.
‎很难看
It's ugly.
很悲伤
And it's sad.
‎还很冷
And it's cold.
‎这里会有倒霉事
Bad things happened here.
‎你说的可是我童年的家
That's my childhood home you're talking about.
‎难怪你这么奇怪
Well, that explains a lot.
‎对不起
Sorry.
‎有些地方让人不寒而栗
Some places just have a chill on them.
‎也许我和我的人能让这里暖和一点
Maybe my people and I can warm it up a little.
‎太宏伟了
It's magnificent.
‎那里
And there.
‎我相信是贝尔蒙特庄园
The Belmont Hold, I believe.
‎我亲爱的女士
This, my dear lady,
‎这可能是现代世界最重要的地方
may be the most important place in the modern world.
‎目前 这是我能想到最好的防守要地
At this moment, it is the best defense I can think of.
‎欢迎来到我家
Welcome to my home.
‎你知道我最担心的是什么吗
You know what bothers me so much?
‎不知道 这个破镇子又迎来美好的一天
No. It's just another lovely day in shit town.
‎有三件事
Three things.
‎很好 慢慢说来
Oh, good. A list.
‎第一 你还是个差劲的人
One: You're still a terrible human being.
‎我从来没说要做别人
Never claimed to be anything else.
‎那也没什么好处
That doesn't make it better.
‎第二 你说得对
Two: You're right.
‎我可能要昏过去了
I may faint dead away.
‎闭嘴
Shut up.
我们总是被动应对 ‎一件事接着一件事
We've been running from event to event,
‎而不是站稳脚跟 主动出击
reacting instead of planting our feet and just acting.
‎但我也被卷入了这场冒险
But I've also been caught up in the adventure.
这让我忘了一些事情
And it's making me forget things.
‎比如
Such as?
‎第三
Third:
这个烂摊子
This mess.
‎他们在做力所能及的事
Well, they're doing what they can.
‎不 他们没有思考
No, they're not thinking.
‎他们都吓坏了
They're in shock.
噢 我知道
Oh, I know.
‎但还是个烂摊子 你看
But it's still a mess. Look.
‎我的族人在世界各地组成了社区
I come from a people who have weaved a community across the world,
‎我知道你了解那个社区是做什么的
and I know you know what that community does.
‎能解决问题
It fixes things,
还能记住过去
and it remembers.
‎我在这里见到的人都忘了过去
All I see here are people who've forgotten.
‎等等
Wait.
‎你
You.
‎是的 你们这些人
Yes, you people.
‎不要用那种眼神看我
No, don't look at me like that.
‎听着 你不能把厕所建在你睡觉和做饭的地方旁边
Listen, you cannot put latrines that close to where you sleep and cook.
‎你们都会生病的
You'll all get sick.
‎这不是难事 你们把食物存放在哪里
This isn't hard. Where are you storing your food?
‎宫廷需要这个
The court needs this.
‎以上帝的名义 ‎你要向统治者献上贡品
You will by God give tribute to your rulers.
‎这可不行
Oh, hell, no!
‎什么
What?
‎你想让人们交出他们能找到的一点食物
You want these people to give up what little food they can find
‎给你不露面的国王和王后吗
to your invisible king and queen?
‎这里对他们来说不安全
It's not safe for them up here.
‎这些人不吃饭对他们也不安全
And it's not safe for these people to give up eating.
‎别碍我的事
Don't get in my way.
‎我知道我们站在同一边
I realize that we are on the same side,
‎但你要知道 我用眼神就能杀了你
but you need to understand that I can kill you by looking at you.
‎我也注意到 这些人需要组织
I also realize that these people need to organize.
‎他们需要…
They need...
‎除非他们自救 否则他们帮不了你
They can't help you until they help themselves.
‎你不露面的国王和王后只能去统治死人
Otherwise, your invisible king and queen will rule over nothing but bones.
‎你觉得他们想要这样吗
Do you think that's what they want?
‎-嗯...  ‎-你觉得呢
- Well... - Do you?
‎不
No.
那你可以帮我
So you can give me a hand.
‎这些车是你的吗
Are these carts yours?
‎不是吗 那些是他的吗
No? Those are his?
‎我们得把东西拉过来
We need to pull them around.
‎我们后面的这些建筑清理干净了吗
Have these buildings behind us been cleared?
‎建筑废弃了
They're abandoned.
‎你不止这点聪明
You are cleverer than that.
‎这个城市到处都是黑暗生物
This city is overrun with night creatures.
‎他们来自某个地方
They're coming from somewhere.
‎第一条原则是保证你的住所安全
First rule is make your shelter safe.
‎你能找些卫兵帮这些人清理建筑吗
Can some of your fellow fighters help these people clear these buildings?
‎如果有地下宫廷的话
If there's an underground court,
‎城市下面肯定有一连串的洞穴
then there's got to be a series of catacombs under the city.
‎像格雷捷特一样
Like Gresit.
‎因为如果地下只有一个藏身地
Because if there was just one underground location,
‎早就被吸血鬼发现了
it would have been found by the vampires already.
‎他们肯定躲在庞大的地道和洞穴网络里
They have to have been hiding inside an extensive network of tunnels and spaces.
‎规模庞大到足以让该死的吸血鬼也在下面筑巢
Extensive enough that the bloody vampires are nesting down there, too.
‎这些家伙无处不在
And these things must be everywhere.
‎我开始这段旅程时 我的计划很简单
When I began this journey, I had a very simple plan.
‎那个计划已经变了
That plan has evolved.
‎现在的计划是征服
The plan is now conquest.
‎你们要杀光所有人
Kill everything you see!
‎除了锻造师赫克托
Except Hector the forgemaster.
‎他只能留给我
He is for me alone.
‎开始
Begin!